campintouch.com 2007-11-02

# CampInTouch - If you went to camp, you'd understand. :: Privacy Statement

| CampInTouch Privacy Policy

CampInTouch does NOT send Spam or sell email addresses. 

About CampInTouch and the Information We Collect  Profile Information submitted by Members to CampInTouch   
CampInTouch is an online social networking community that connects people through networks of camps by communicating, sharing, making new friends, and finding old friends. To accomplish this, each CampInTouch Member creates his or her own profile within their camp network, which contains the personal information that the Member chooses to include. This personal information includes such things as: 

A. First name or first and last names of the Member (depending on the options selected by the Member),   
B. Gender, age, martial status and other, similar personal information,   
C. Occupation,   
D. Schools attended or companies with whom the Member is associated,   
F. Location (e.g., city and state), and   
G. Photos, videos or other shared content uploaded by the Member to his or her profile, to the extent that it includes personal information.   

Other Information submitted by Members to CampInTouch   
CampInTouch also collects Member-submitted account information such as name and email address, to identify Members and send notifications related to the use of the CampInTouch service. You should also be aware that Members may reveal other personal information while communicating on other areas of the CampInTouch website, such as while sharing memories, stories, questions of the week, etc.  This information, in turn, may be viewed by other members of your specific camp network.  No visitors or members of other camp networks can access your information. 

Information Not Directly Submitted by Members or Other Website Users to CampInTouch   
Finally, we also collect some information from Members, as well as from other visitors to the CampInTouch website, that is not personally identifiable, such as browser type and IP address. This information is gathered from all Members and visitors to the website. 

Use of Information Obtained by CampInTouch 

Other Information submitted by Members to CampInTouch

Except where a Member might choose to include a full name in his or her profile, a Member's email address and full name will only be used in the following circumstances: 

A. When the Member invites a friend via email to become a CampInTouch Member,   
B. When we send notifications to the Member relating to his or her use of the CampInTouch service or CampInTouch website, and   
C. When we send regular notifications, weekly updates, or other news regarding the CampInTouch service or the CampInTouch website.   

Except when inviting friends, a Member's email address will never be shared with or displayed to any other person. Members and their bunkmates, and other Members within their camp networks communicate on CampInTouch with each other through the CampInTouch service, without disclosing email addresses. 

Information that Members do not submit to us   
We use information relating to the server information, IP address, and browser-type. 

Sharing of the Information this Site Gathers/Tracks   
Except as explained above, or where you are expressly informed otherwise, we do not sell, rent, share, trade or give away any of your personal information, unless required by law or for the protection of your Membership. However, CampInTouch may share profile information and aggregate usage information in a non-personally identifiable manner with advertisers and other third parties in order to present to Members and other users of the CampInTouch website more targeted advertising, products and services. In such situations we will never disclose information that would personally identify you. 

Links   
The CampInTouch Website contains links to other websites. This includes links that are placed there by CampInTouch (such as in advertisements), as well as by other CampInTouch Members. Please be aware that CampInTouch is not responsible for the privacy practices of any other website. We encourage all Members and other users of the CampInTouch website to be aware of when they leave our website, and to read the privacy policies of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy policy applies solely to information collected by CampInTouch through the CampInTouch website. 

Use of Cookies   
A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on the CampInTouch website. However, we do not and will not use cookies to collect private information from any Member or other user of the CampInTouch website which they did not intentionally submit to us, other than as stated in this Privacy Policy.   
We use both "session ID cookies" and "persistent cookies." We use session ID cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. A session ID cookie expires when you close you browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. Note also that Members may optionally use a cookie to remember their email in order to automatically log in to our website. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser's "help" file; however, please note that, if you reject cookies or disable cookies in your web browser, you may not be able to use the CampInTouch website. 

Correcting/Updating or Removing Information   
YOU CAN ALWAYS CHANGE THE PERSONAL INFORMATION YOU'VE SUBMITTED TO THE CAMPINTOUCH WEBSITE, INCLUDING THE INFORMATION INCLUDED IN YOUR CAMPINTOUCH PROFILE, BY CLICKING THE "EDIT PROFILE" LINK ON YOUR CAMPINTOUCH PROFILE PAGE. 

Changes in Our Privacy Policy   
If we change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on our web site so Members and other users of the CampInTouch website are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If we are going to use Members' or other users' personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify those Members and users via email or by placing a prominent notice on our website. 

Invite a Friend   
If a Member elects to use our "Invite" feature to invite a friend to become a Member of the CampInTouch service, we ask them for the friend's email address. CampInTouch will automatically send the friend an email inviting them to join the site. CampInTouch stores this email address for the purpose of automatically adding the respondent to the friends list of the Member sending the invitation, and also to send reminders of the invitation. CampInTouch will never sell these email addresses or use them to send any other communication besides invitations and invitation reminders. Any person who receives an invitation may contact  CampInTouch to request the removal of this information from our database. 

Security   
The CampInTouch account of every Member is password-protected.  CampInTouch takes every precaution to protect the information of the Members, as well as information collected from other users of the CampInTouch website. We use industry standard measures to protect all information that is stored on our servers and within our database. We limit the access to this information to those employees who need access to perform their job function such as our customer service personnel. If you have any questions about the security at our website, please [contact us](http://www.campintouch.com/content/14.html). 

Email Choice/Opt-out   
Members who no longer wish to receive our email updates or other email notifications may opt-out of receiving these communications by following the instructions on our website. 

Third Party Advertising   
The ads appearing on this Web site are delivered to Members by our Web advertising partners. Our Web advertising partners may use cookies. Doing this allows the ad network to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement. In this way, ad networks may compile information about where you, or others who are using your computer, saw their advertisements and determine which ads are clicked on. This information allows an ad network to deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. CampInTouch does not have access to or control of the cookies that may be placed on the computer of any Member or other user of the CampInTouch website by the third-party ad servers or ad networks. 

This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by CampInTouch only, and does not cover the use of cookies by any other party. 

Members and Users Located Outside of the United States of America   
We have made an effort to protect the personal information of all Members and other users of the CampInTouch website, and to the extent applicable, we attempt to comply with local data protection and consumer rights laws. If you are unsure whether this privacy policy is in conflict with the applicable local rules where you are located, you should not submit your personal information to the CampInTouch website. IN ADDITION, IF YOU ARE LOCATED WITHIN THE EUROPEAN UNION, YOU SHOULD NOTE THAT YOUR INFORMATION WILL BE TRANSFERRED TO THE UNITED STATES, THE LAWS OF WHICH MAY BE DEEMED BY THE EUROPEAN UNION TO HAVE INADEQUATE DATA PROTECTION (see, for example, European Union Directive 95/46/EC of 24 October 1995, a copy of which can be found here). Members and other users of the CampInTouch website located in countries outside of the United States of America who submit personal information do thereby consent to the general use of such information as provided in this privacy policy and to the transfer of that information to and/or storage of the information in the United States of America. 

Contacting CampInTouch   
If you have any questions about this privacy policy, CampInTouch's privacy practices, or your dealings with CampInTouch, please [contact us](http://www.campintouch.com/content/14.html).
